ようこそ、こんにちは！
XXX
デンマークの言葉では "Goddag og velkommen"
セッションのタイトルは Unity Hacks です。
The title of the
自己紹介から始めましょう。
by introducing myself.
私の名前は Emil Johansen です。
My name is Emil Johansen
オンライン上では普段 AngryAnt のニックネームを使ってます。
nickname of AngryAnt online.
私の写真です。
That's a photo of me
私は Unity に勤めるゲーム開発者であり、仕事は様々な開発チームと一緒に作業をして
with the different developer teams to ensure that
Unity の様々な異なる機能が正しく連動することを保証して、そのうえで内部でのデモ作成をします。
together, and I do internal demo work.
作業のいくらかは標準アセットに組み込まれたり、というようなものです。
assets and that sort of thing.
さらに AI は専門分野です。
And I specialize in AI as well.
Unity には 4 年間勤めて来ました。
I've been at Unity for four years.
また過去 5 年間 Unity 製品に取り組んでいます。
worked with Unity the product.
その前は Unreal エンジン 3、CryEngine 1、さらに Renderware に関わってました。
Engine 3, CryEngine 1, and Renderware
デンマークのコペンハーゲンに住んでます。
I live in Copenhagen, Denmark.
暇な時間をみつけては Path および Behave など追加的な プロジェクトを作成しています。
additional projects such as Path and Behave.
これらは Unity の AI ミドルウェアです。
solutions for Unity.
今回は二度目のアジアツアーです。
This is my second time around on the Asia Tour.
昨年は「高速ネットワークおよび AI 対応したゲーム開発」のトピックでセッションをしました。
Network and AI-Ready Game Development."
トピックの名前が長いタイトルですみませんが、
I'm sorry about that, but
正直短い名前が思いつきませんでした。
I couldn't come up with a shorter one.
今回は昨年のセッションの実用編のようなものです。
counterpart of that talk from last year.
私のウェブサイトは AngryAnt.com です。
My website is AngryAnt.com.
コードスニペット、サンプル、プロジェクト、および
And I gather some of my code snippets, examples, projects and
ビデオを収集すること、例えば昨年セッションの取りまとめにも取り組んでます。
videos such as the recording of last year's talk.
私の娘のリリーです。
This is my daughter, Lily.
本日は少し違う眼鏡をつけてます。
different set of glasses.
ファッションの意味合いではなく、私の 2 月の誕生日に娘にバラバラにされてしまったからです。
in February, she chose to tear the old pair apart.
まったく小悪魔ってやつですね。
So she's a feisty little devil.
こんな可愛い子を責められないですよね。
her with those looks.
そろそろセッションの内容に入りましょうか。
Let's jump onto the contents of this talk.
本日の他のセッション内容と違って、
Unlike some of the other talks today, I've tried to
遊び要素を取り入れてみようと考えてみました。
fun playful kind of thing.
願わくば、いくつかのサンプルをあなた自身が
examples I'm going to show here
後でそのまま利用できると良いですね。
and if not use them directly.
その目的で設計していますが、さらに
I really hope that you can
いくつかのアイデアやアプローチを使って、刺激を受けて
and hopefully be inspired by that
自身の Unity Hack を作成してほしいものです。
to create your own Unity hacks.
今日のテーマは、「ミッション名：そのままリリースに活用しよう」です。
Mission: Let's Just Ship This Thing.
そこが昨年セッションとつながるところです。
with last year's talk as well.
必要なワークロードを最小化するために賢く作業する、という要素がひとつあります。
needed workload by working smart.
そのためには、データ、コードを再利用すべき、という面があり本日はそのデモをいくつか取り上げます。
I'll go in and demonstrate in a few ways.
もう一つの側面は 反復作業時間を短縮するために
And another part is shaving iteration
time as closely as possible
作業ワークフローを管理することです。
by managing your workflow.
これも後で取り上げます。
We'll also get into that.
反復時間を短縮するため、ワークフローを調整して
that means adapting your workflow
関連するフィードバックデータを出来るかぎり速く取得して
data as quickly as possible
必要なマニュアル作業を短縮することです。
of manual work required.
全般には、「十分である」というテーマの話を通して
a theme of "Good Enough" can ship
高速ゲーム開発にとって重要かを見ていきます。
game development.
このコンテンツを取り上げるにあたり
presenting this content is
大量の優れた Hack およびコードをお見せして
of cool hacks and code
データ再利用や
of examples of data reuse
エディタ スクリプティングの良い事例を沢山見ていきます。
and a lot of editor scripting.
ランタイムのサンプルをみて始めましょうか。
some examples from the runtime.
最初はアニメーションカーブのテーマについて触れます。
the subject of animation curves.
最初のサンプルはキャラクターの方向スピード（Directional Speed）です。
directional speed of character.
多くのゲームではヒューマノイド キャラクターまたはアバターを動かす必要があります。
character or some avatar you need to move around.
このアバターには Facing と Heading を持ちます。
facing and a heading.
デフォルトでは Facing と Heading が等しいとき、
to heading, you'll want to
キャラクターはトップスピードで移動します。
move that character by the top speed.
ある角度にあるとき、最初の 20 度かそこらまでは角度や速度を保ちます。
twenty degrees or so, keep this angle or this constant speed.
一方で横に移動したり
moving more sideways
後ろ方向に動く時、ベース速度（Base Speed）に重みづけします。
you want to weight the base speed.
当然、これは反対方向もミラーされます。
works mirrored as well.
アニメーションカーブにおいて、お勧めする方法のひとつは
this with animation curves
角度を分割、または拡大縮小して Facing の中の Heading を、
is to divide the angle, or basically scale the
angle between the heading in the facing
ゼロと 180 度の間で調整し
between 0 and 180 degrees
正規化することです。
and normalize that.
これによりアニメーションカーブを定義して、カーブの高さを使用して
where you can use the height of the curve to
スピードの大きさを定義できます。
define the scale of the speed.
このサンプルでは、さきほどデモをしたカーブをお見せして
the curve that I demonstrated earlier
ゼロに近づくにつれて、カーブが前に進んで、スピードは 1 のままです。
to zero - moving forward, the speed remains 1.
1 または 180 度に向かうにつれて速度は半分に落ちます。
degrees, we go down to half-speed.
実際の環境で見てみます。
Showing this in a real environment.
前に進むと、スピードが速いことが分かります。
I have quite a lot of speed.
スピードのインジケータが右上隅に表示されてます。
in the upper-right corner.
動き回るにつれて
But as I move around, I get
Heading に対して Facing がどう動くかにもとづいてスピードが異なります。
moves around compared to the facing.
スクリプトをみてみます。
So, looking at a script.
使用しているスクリプトは比較的簡単なものです。
The script I'm using for this is fairly simple.
実際には、もっともスペースをとるのは
up the most space is just
入力をとって、方向ベクトルを構成するところです。
that into a directional vector.
このため、これは入力軸を取得するのみです。
the input axis.
そして各々の Update の中で、この例では Transform の Translate を行なって
Then in each update, I just, for this
example, translate the transform
Directional ベクトルおよび
where I translate it by
デフォルト スピード（今回は 5）により Translate します。
the default speed, which is at 5.
Update であるため、 Time.DeltaTime によりスケールが行なわれます。
it's scaled by Time. DeltaTime.
面白いところは Transform の Forward ベクトルと 方向ベクトル(Direction)のなす角度をとって
the forward vector of the transform and my direction
180で割ることにより正規化することです。
thus normalizing it.
次に Speed Scale という名前の アニメーションカーブを評価(Evaluate)します。
curve called Speed Scale
これは public にしているため、エディタで適切に表示されるよう定義できます。
exactly how it needs to look in the editor.
Evaluate 関数をコールすることで任意の Time Index におけるカーブの高さが取得できます。
of the curve at my given time index.
アニメーションカーブのもうひとつの例はカメラの Blending および Clamping で使用することです。
using it for camera blending and clamping.
同じセットアップにおいて、Heading または Facing のあるキャラクターと、
with heading or a facing
キャクラターの上部を写すカメラがあり、
top of the character
通常はキャラクターの頭部の少し上を写しています。
the head of the character.
比較的良くあるセットアップはカメラの動作を Clamp して
to clamp the movement of the camera
上限および下限の角度で
and a lower angle
またはその逆で制限します。または基本的に、キャラクター後ろの Facing ベクトル にします。
the backwards facing vector of the character.
And you commonly also have a bit of logic to handle
clipping of objects, so you move the camera closer.
In this case I'm not using an
animation curve between 0 and 1
because I want additional data.
I actually want two
data points out of this
I want to know what the lower
and upper maximum is
as well as I want to know what the
update speed of the camera should be.
So I'm using the time index of the
animation curve to define the
upper and lower bounds in degrees.
So this basically says that
it can go 20 degrees below
the backwards facing vector,
and 30 degrees above.
And then I use the height to specify how
quickly it can move toward these extremes.
The effect of this is that as we are above medium,
and continue to move forward or upward
the camera will update
slower and slower.
So instead of getting a hard
clamp, we get a nice soft
lead into that clamping
and the same in reverse.
So if we look at the same example,
and I move the camera up
I keep a constant speed of the cursor.
But even so
it moves slowly in the end.
Taking a look at the code for this
this is slight more complex, so I'm
going to just focus on a few key points.
Initially, I define my animation
curve called "VerticalSpan"
where I set the default values to
start from the keyframe, minus 20
and end on the keyframe, 30.
And initially I just set it to have a start and
end value of 1, so this is just a flat curve.
I then use the editor to go in and add this
scale on either end to get that bell shape.
Then I have a few simple properties for figuring out a
normalized position on the arc that the camera can move on.
And finally, when I update my camera,
I have a "targetHorizontalRotation"
which an input scripts provides for me.
I then initially figure out the speed at which should
update this camera position or camera rotation.
If the vertical position
is above half,
and we're continuing up,
then I take my update speed and scale
it by the evaluated vertical span
using the angle as the index, because
remember we used angles for the X-axis.
If we are up, but we're not
continuing further up
this logic will not get executed, so therefore
we will just keep the regular update speed.
And the same is valid for the reverse.
So then I update my rotation.
And I apply the second step of checking
if my angle goes beyond either extreme.
So I clamp it and that's it.
So just to recap.
Animation curves are basically
just a number of curved 2D values.
So while they are most useful for, and
initially designed for animation
and these two examples were
probably quite animation related
you can basically use them
for just about anything.
Since you can just sample the data at
any point; it's just simple 2D data.
One example, I saw a guy on Twitter
recently who had used it to
he used an animation curve to define the difficulty level
of his different scenes, which is a very nice use case.
So anything from game logic to AI
whatever you can come up with,
we need a set of 2D values.
Especially because the curves are
visually editable in the editor, so
you can, very easily, instead of
spending a lot of time iterating over
some magical numbers, or a certain bit of
code that does something programmatically
you can basically just
go, "Here's a curve,"
and send it to your
game designer or artist
and go, "Okay, so you go ahead and tweak this."
And they can do this in play mode.
It's a very nice way to reduce iteration time
and offset a task that really should
belong to the game designer or an artist
offset that away from the programmer who
would otherwise become a bottleneck.
Additionally, it's a visual thing, so it's
easy to debug and understand what's going on.
For one example, I used
an animation curve
not as the source of the data,
but as a visual tool
because I had some programmatic animation going on, and
I didn't quite understand why it behaved the way it did.
So my solution for it was to, at
runtime, create an animation curve
and every frame, or every
N-number frames
insert an animation key,
key framing it
so I could visually see what was going on,
and that helped me to very quickly
go in and change that bit of
logic that was misbehaving.
Moving onto data reuse
in this example going to talk
a bit about a stealth system.
So, in many games where you have a dark environment
it's common that you have some sort of sneak mechanic where
the level of lighting you're in determines
how well an enemy character can see you.
And the way this is usually done is
by setting up these trigger volumes
for determining that at this point you're in
shadow, but at this point you're not.
This has several problems because
these basically give you two
pieces of data to update every time
you make a change to your level.
Not only do you have to change your
lighting, but also these logical triggers.
It also gives a fairly bad
user experience because when
the character is in this position, he's in
light, but when he's there, he's in dark
which is quite jarring
and strange for the user.
Actually many games ship with having an out of
sync update where they update the lighting
and they forget, in their rush to to finish the
game, they forget to update the logic triggers
and then all of a sudden you
have a lot of very angry users.
So what I've done in this case is
instead of this direct break
I have a sliding scale for how
much in shadow the character is.
Which I'm gonna show you how I do here.
The way this works is basically in Unity 3.5, I believe
we added the system of light probes.
Initially, this system was added in order to give you
something that seems like realtime lighting using baked data.
So you get them the nice realtime lighting feel using
baked global illumination without the runtime overhead.
So what I do here is basically use the same system
to get just the basic lighting information out.
Since we have full global illumination
here, I have all sorts of
directional values as well, but I found
that for this use case, actually just
getting the common
lighting is sufficient
I then take some numbers which are
fitted to this particular level.
So in this example, these are constant values, but
they should probably, in an actual use case, be
per-level defined because each level's
lighting is a bit different, and
the idea of what is shadow
and not is different.
But I basically just scale the lighting between
these two values and normalize it.
And that gives me a nice normalized value
of whether you're in shadow or not.
So just to summarize, we are
reusing existing data here
which means there's
no duplicated effort.
You change your lighting,
you rebake, and that's it.
It also means that what the user sees is
what he actually gets in terms of game logic.
So there's no disconnect for the user.
And it's high quality data unlike the the
simple trigger volumes, you can have
much more varied
gameplay where maybe
the AI has been implemented so it kind of almost
sees the character and goes closer to investigate
and then you can maybe
move further into shadow.
And it's very intuitive to maintain.
You change the light, you hit bake, you're done.
Finally, there's no runtime overhead for this.
This is using a system that's already there
it's simply sampling between
some values and interpolating
so it's extremely low-cost.
I'm gonna show you a small
example of a menu set up here.
So this is just a quick example menu
with a main menu and some level
setup, settings, and so forth.
It's not really exciting, but if we look at the
code, things start getting a bit more interesting.
So the idea here is that
once the script starts up
based on my "State enum" definition, I create
a dictionary indexed by this "State enum"
pointing to action delicate handlers.
So way this is built is basically that I used reflection
to find any function that matches the prefix "on"
the name of the state, and
the postfix "MenuGUI"
So for the default value of
"State. Main" I'll get
a dictionary index of "State. Main"
pointing to function called "OnMainMenuGUI."
This means the first
iteration of "onGUI"
I call the delegate pointed to by the dictionary
indexed by the current state being "Main"
That will invoke the
"OnMainMenuGUI" GUI handler.
Switching between different menus is simply a matter
of changing the value of the state variable
which will then either call on "LevelsMenuGUI,"
on "SettingsMenuGUI," or on "CreditsMenuGUI"
これは直感的で可読性の高いセットアップです。
setup easily readable.
これを少しみてきます。これは良いサンプルコードの再利用の例であり、
nice example code reuse where
間違えるポイントを簡単に限定します。
the points of failure on this.
関数名と列挙型の名前に不整合がなければ正しく動作します。
name, and the enum name, or it will just work.
ごく自然な文法です。
It's a very natural syntax.
列挙方を記述して、関数を記述して、それだけで何が行われているかわかります。
you can easily see what's going on.
自己完結する WebPlayer のサンプルに移ります。
self-contained WebPlayer
この場で実際にビルドしてみて、うまく行くかみてみます。
it here, and see if everything breaks or not.
これはシンプルなサンプルであり、ウェブサイト JavaScript があって
have a bit of website JavaScript which
WebPlayer に戻るメッセージを送信する内容です。
sends a message back to my WebPlayer.
このスクリプトがセットアップされている方法をみていきます。
this script is set up
public である TextAsset 変数があり、
TextAsset variable
Start で ExternalEval 関数をコールして、その際にテキストアセットのテキストコンテンツを使用して
text content of that text asset
そして JavaScript がコールする JavaScript コールバックのメソッドを提供します。
method for JavaScript to call.
ではこの JavaScript コードをみてましょう。
If we look at JavaScript code for this.
それがここにある JavaScript の全てです。これで基本的に
It basically gets a reference to
WebPlayer 参照が取得できて、このゲームオブジェクトのコールした関数にメッセージ送信して
game object called this function
戻り値がウェブサイトの JavaScript関数 prompt となります。
JavaScript function "prompt."
結果的に、直感的で分かりやすくなります。
So, very straightforward and easy to understand.
ここで続けてみるとします。
If we continue here.
その場合のメリットは、関連するコードがプロジェクトに全て含まれているということで
relevant code contained within that project
すなわちバージョン管理がより直感的になるということです。外部の依存関係がありません。
You have no external dependencies.
ウェブサイト JavaScript に変更を加えたときは
your website JavaScript
関連する C# または Unity の JavaScript コードで変更セットと組み合わせることが出来ます。
with the relevant C# or Unity JavaScript code.
ビルドして実行するプロジェクトがひとつのみであるため、テストや開発がより楽になります。
just have one project to build and run, and that's it.
それでは高速ゲーム開発について再度まとめると
rapid game development.
昨年に Rapid Game Developmentという セッションは
Last year's talk by this title,
AngryAnt.com/videos のビデオで利用可能です。
it's available on AngryAnt.com/videos.
この話を手土産にしてもらったところで
With this talk in baggage
この次に話す内容のほうがより便利なはずです。
this other talk will probably
be a bit more useful.
次はエディタに関連したところ、そして最初はインポータから見ていきます。
and initially looking at importers.
最初のサンプルはパッケージのセットアップに関するものです。
My first example is about package setup.
これはアセットストアのパッケージまたは、複数のプロジェクトで再利用するコードで使用するものです。
code that you reuse a lot between different projects.
もしスクリプト以外の依存関係があり、それがテクスチャなどでなく、
which aren't a texture or something,
Player Settings などのプロジェクトセットアップといったケースの場合に
player settings, or whatever that might be,
今回紹介する方法が役に立ちます。
this is what I'm addressing here.
サンプルとして：
As an example:
カスタムアセットにいくつかのタグ、レイヤー、および Input Axisが含まれているとします。
some tags, layers, and input axis.
これは特定の Input セットアップを必要とするキャラクターコントローラがあり、
This is quite useful if you have a charactercontroller which requires a specific input setup
プロジェクト間で共有したい場合にかなり便利です。
this between projects.
Tim Cooper が先ほど話をしたシリアライゼーション システムを使用して
system which Tim Cooper talked about earlier
Unity のセットアップがこのスクリプトで必要とする内容にマッチさせることが出来ます。
match what this script requires.
これは優れたソリューションです。
It's a very nice solution.
ここでのサンプルとしてカスタムのアセットにレイヤーを追加した後は、インポートを行って
to my custom asset here, I can hit import
レイヤーに遷移して、追加されたことが確認できます。
can see it has been added here.
そして同様に、レイヤーを変更し再エクスポートをするとここで更新されます。
and go re-export it, it updates here.
これにより依存関係を容易に変更できるようになります。
move dependencies around.
ワークフロー自動化に移ります。
Moving onto workflow automation.
ここで主要な目的は共通する反復タスクを削減することです。
common, repetitive tasks.
最終的にチームのモチベーション向上にもつながります。
boost your team morale.
誰だって多くの機械作業は止めたいところです。
of the factory work.
反復作業の時間も短縮して生産性もあがります。
time since you can produce more.
ここでのサンプルとして、作業した Android プラグインを準備しました。
plugin that I want to work with.
基本的に、このコードを最初に書いたのは Android プラグインを扱うときで、
first time I wanted to do Android plugins
自分は Java が得意でなく、
because my Java is not the best
そして Java コードで何回も反復が必要になり、
lot of iterations on this Java code
バグフィックスが多く必要になると分かっていたためです。
and fix a lot of bugs.
Android プラグインを使用する現在のワークフローは多くのコマンドラインを必要としていて
Android plugin involves a lot of command line
手動のコーディングや手動の実行作業が必要です。
hand coding or hand execution.
これは非常にシンプルなテストであり
a function that'll call back to.
先ほどみたウェブサイト JavaScript のように Unity にコールバックする関数が提供されます。
JavaScript we saw before.
コンパイルをした方法について、
The way that I have this compiling
基本的に C# で普段使用しているのと同じワークフローとしたいため
workflow that I'm used to with C#
アセットのポストプロセッサを記述しました。
so I wrote an asset post processor.
これによりファイルを検索したり、Assets/Plugins/Android/src パスにあるファイルをハンドリング出来ます。
any file within the path "Assets/Plugins/Android/src"
この拡張子が .java である場合、全ての Java コードをコンパイルしてきます。
I want to compile all my Java code.
そのためには、基本的に .NET プロセスのスタート情報を使用して
using the .net process start info
ビルトインされた Java コンパイラを起動します。
system Java compiler
プロジェクトの Java ファイルについて
I parse in the Java files in my project
Android jar ファイルへの参照として
the reference to the
Android jar file
Android SDK から、そして Unity jar ファイル、等々とパースしていきます。
from the Android SDK, and the
Unity jar file, and so forth
さらに必要な署名を作成します。
I also create the signature needed
最後にプロジェクトに含める jar としてビルドします。
finally just build it into a
jar which I put in my project.
結果的に得られたワークフローは、Java コードを保存することで、
The resulting workflow is basically
that I save my Java code
ここで実際に行ってみます。
which we can just quickly do here.
ここでコンパイラエラーを作成して、コンソール上に表示されます。
I get that compiler error in my console.
サクサクと作業を行って「この行をじゃあ変更しようか」として、すぐコンパイルできます。
go and change that," and there we go, it's compiled.
すなわち、ワークフローを普段と同じ方法で最適化できるということです。
in a way that I'm used to working with.
バンドルのトピックに移ります。
So moving onto a topic of bundles.
初めに、バンドルのマニフェストについてカバーします。
about is the manifest for bundles.
ここで実現したいことは、手動でない更新のアプローチであり、
want to have a hands-off update approach
バンドルの何かを変更するとき、手動のステップが沢山あることを避けます。
don't want to have a lot of manual steps.
そして、そこのアセットに実行時に直接アクセスできるようにします。
at runtime to the assets in there.
I don't want to have a lot of runtime code which searches
by name and all this stuff because that's not very
solid in the end; you'll get
a lot of errors from that.
要するにシンプルな Scriptable オブジェクトのカスタムアセットです。
simple scriptable object custom asset.
この中心となるのは、プレハブのリストがあるため、プレハブAnd the core of this is it has a list of prefabs,
so this is a bundle manifest for prefabs.
このリストを認識して、オブジェクトの追加および ID を通したアクセスを提供します。
accesses for adding an object and accessing it by ID.
ランタイムの場合でも同じように出来ます。
The runtime equivalent of this.
一回バンドルのメインアセットとしてバンドルを生成されたマニフェストでビルドすれば
manifest as the main asset of the bundle
バンドルがダウンロードされれば
I can simply, once the bundle has been downloaded,
中に入って
I can go in and
バンドルのメインアセットをマニフェストの型にキャストできます。
the bundle to my manifest type.
一回それがあれば、マニフェストへの参照を求めて
reference to that manifest to give me
プレハブへの参照をすでに把握している ID にもとづき得られます。
the ID that I already know.
ここでは探す作業はありません。バンドルのビルドプロセスに格納できるIDというだけです。
which I can store in my build process of the bundle.
プレハブ バンドルの強いようのサンプルを示します。
Here's an example of prefab bundle use.
ここでのゴールはやはり、自然なワークフローであり
same natural workflow
シンプルなデプロイ ビルドのメソッドです。
a simple deploy build method.
今回のセットアップでは、.prefabBundle フォルダを準備して
I have this ".prefabBundle" folder
ビルドスクリプトは .prefabBundle の名前のフォルダにある全てのプレハブを見つけます。
and my build script just goes in and finds all
prefabs in any folder called ".prefabBundle"
これが ボックスコライダ および キューブのあるもとのプレハブです。
has a box collider and a cube on it.
ビルドスクリプトが実行されると、以前にみてきたようにマニフェストを自動生成するので、
the manifest here as we saw before,
このプレハブへの参照があり、また ID もあります。
prefab here, and it has an ID.
次に行うことは参照プレハブを作成することです。
creates a reference prefab.
このセットアップで便利なところはゲームを通常のようにプレハブを使用してゲームをビルドすることであり、
my game using prefabs like I normally would
後でバンドルを使用することを心配する必要がありません。
to use bundles later on
バンドルをビルドするか、シーンをプレハブでビルドして
go build my scenes with prefabs
バンドルでまとめたいプレハブを、prefabBundle フォルダに入れて
up, put them in a prefabBundle folder
ビルドプロセスによりシーンのインスタンスを字度王的に参照バンドルまたは参照プレハブに置き換えます。
in my scene with these reference bundles or reference prefabs.
実行モードを抜けると、
here, you can see
ビルドされたために、私の素晴らしいキューブが表示されます。
since it has been built
バンドル プレハブ の参照にはバンドル ID および
which holds the bundle ID
プレハブ ID がバンドル内に格納されています。
and the prefab ID within that bundle.
それを除いては、その他の情報は全てバンドルにプッシュされています。
has now been pushed to the bundle.
つまり、ロードしたときに
So this means when we load this up
キューブが少し後のタイミング、すなわち
appears a bit later
バンドルーがロードされてインスタンス化されたとき、参照されたデータにもとづいて表示されます。
based on the data in the reference.
次に別のバンドル使用方法の例を挙げます。
Here's another example of bundle use.
通常はバンドルに追加のコードを含めることが出来ません。
additional code in a bundle.
全てのコードはコアのゲームにビルドインされる必要があり
built into the core game
そして追加のアセットはアセットバンドルに含めることが出来ます。
then be put in an asset bundle.
しかし、いくつかのケースにおいては
where you might want to
コードをバンドルに入れたい場合があり、例えば追加のキャラクター
you have an additional character
または武器か何かでカスタムロジックがあるものがあるようなケースかもしれません。
which has some custom logic to it.
同じプロジェクトに全てのスクリプトがある、お馴染みのワークフローをしたいはずです。
of having all your scripts in the same project.
全てがメインプロジェクトにコンパイルされませんが、ワークフローは同様です。
project, but the same kind of workflow.
私が実装した方法は
implementing this is I have
Script Bundles というフォルダを Assets/WebPlayer templates というフォルダに入れることでした。
folder called "Assets/WebPlayer templates."
この特定のフォルダについて重要なことは
this particular folder
WebPlayer templates のフォルダについて、コンパイラおよび全てのインポータがオフになっていることです。
the compiler and all importers are turned off.
この理由はウェブプレイヤー テンプレートがJavaScript コードを含むかもしれず、
might contain JavaScript code
これがウェブサイト JavaScript であり
which is website JavaScript
当然にメインプロジェクトに含まれてほしくないためです。
compiled in with your main project.
この事実を利用して
But we're taking advantage of that fact
スクリプトバンドル フォルダを入れて
bundle folder in there
ビルドスクリプトは、このフォルダの全てのサブフォルダを検索して
all subfolders of this folder
その中の全てのスクリプトを .NET アセンブリにコンパイルし、
and compiling them to a .net assembly
その際に以前みた Java コンパイルの時に似たテクニックを用います。
you saw used for Java compiling before.
基本的に .NET プロセスのセットアップを使用して、Unityに同梱されアセンブリにビルドインされた .NET コンパイラを実行します。
compiler that was shipped with Unity, and built in assembly.
And this assembler saves it out as a text
asset by calling it "myassembly.bytes"
この拡張により Unity がテキストアセットとしてインポートして
import it as a text asset
テキストエンコードはしないため、重要なバイナリデータは失いません。
so you don't lose any important binary data.
つまりアセットをアセットバンドルに含めて
asset in an asset bundle
そしてテキストバンドルしてアクセスしてメモリにロードできます。
bundle and load it into memory.
これはこのすぐ後にお見せします。
And I can show you this in a minute.
バンドルマネージャに移動します。
If we go to the bundle manager...
これは先ほど見たバンドルマネージャです
we took a look at before
型をロードするためのコアルーチンがあり
into load a type
これは要するにバンドルを初期ロードします。
loads the bundle.
そして利用可能になったとき
And once it's available...
ここまで作成したアセンブリであるメインアセットにアクセスします。
for this which is the assembly that I've built.
これはテキストアセットなのでキャストします。
so I can cast it.
そして .bytes プロパティをアクセスすることで
And accessing its .bytes property gives me
.NET アセンブリの .Load に渡すバイト配列を取得します。
into the .net assembly. Load.
この中から探している型を取得できます。
the type that I'm looking for.
これを活用したコードをみていきます。
code that uses this...
ここではバンドルマネージャに
manager to load
NewBehaviorScript 型を BestScriptsEver のバンドルからロードします。
the bundle called "BestScriptsEver."
完了した後、OnReceiveType メソッドが呼ばれるようにします。
called "OnReceiveType" to be invoked.
これにより型の検索に使用した文字列に加えて、型が渡されます。
search for the type, plus the type itself.
型参照を取得した後、現在のゲームオブジェクトのコンポーネントとして追加できます。
add it as a component to my current game object.
その結果はここで見ることが出来ます。
The result of which, you can see here.
ここに追加のスクリプトがあることが確認出来ます。
additional script here
Unity では追加の情報がありません。スクリプトの名前もなく、
There's no script name or anything
その理由はランタイム時に
because it's a component
we have loaded at runtime.
これより興味深いことがあります。
A bit more interesting than this.
もしログをチェックすると、二つのログメッセージがあります：「We're in!」（中にいます）、
messages here: One called "We're in!"
もう一つは "From a script bundle even." （スクリプト バンドル からです）
and then one saying "From
a script bundle even."
これがセットアップされている方法により、私がコンパイルしたコンポーネントのコードをみると
code for the component I've compiled in here
メッセージのログを残す必要があり、それは見てきた二種類ですが
messages, the two that we saw
一つはプリコンパイラ定義に含まれています。
but one is within a pre-compiler define.
これによって、バンドルを自動ビルドすると
automatically build your bundle, you can
バンドルに含まれている、いない場合にあわせてロジックを組むこと出来ます。
whether it's in a bundle or not.
当然ながら .NET コンパイラを実行しているだけなので、追加のセットアップは様々な種類で行うことが出来ます。
compiler, you can have all sorts of additional setup.
例えばひとつのお勧めの方法は、アセンブリの参照として同じフォルダからのリソースを含めることです。
from the same folder as references on the assembly.
はい、それでは最後のまとめです。
Okay, so just in summary.
これは先ほど述べたように、昨年のセッションの実践編にあたります。
practical counterpart from last year's talk
本日の話が刺激になり、また役立つ内容であったことを期待します。
inspirational and useful.
当然ですが、アジアツアーが終わり次第、このコードおよびサンプルその他はすべて利用可能とする予定です。
and examples and all that stuff will be available.
それに加えて、皆さんが帰られてからもご自身がすでにお持ちの
home and think about how you can use
データをどのように利用できるかにより生産性やワークフローをどう最適化するか考えるきっかけとしていただけることを願います。
different purposes to optimize productivity and workflow.
繰り返しになりますが、これは再利用および再適用、ワークフローに関することです。
re-application, and again, workflow.
以上です。もしご質問ありましたら1-2分ほど時間ありますね。今なければ後でもいるので受け付けます。
have like a minute or two. Otherwise, I'll be around for a while.
そして必要ならば誰か通訳をしてくださるとおもいます。
someone to help translate. Thank you.
それでは質問はいかがですか？
Do we have time for questions?
質問をひとつぐらい受ける時間ありますね。
We have one question.
あれ、質問はありませんか？
No? Well that's easy!
はい、そこの方が挙手されてますね。
Oh, there's one here.
（日本語で質問）
[Speaking in Japanese]
はい。アジアツアーを通してわずかに修正はかけていくかもしれません。
to this as I go through on the Asia Tour.
予定としてはスライドやサンプルをこのビデオセッションと同じタイミングでリリースすることです。
the same time as we release the videos of the talks
プロジェクトはすでに GitHubにアップされてます。
already on GitHub
ビデオセッションが利用可能になれば、リポジトリをオンラインまたは公開設定にする予定です。
then I flip that repository online or public.
なので最終的に、見ていただいた全てを公開予定です。
here will be made available.
ご拝聴いただきまして有難う御座いました。
Okay, thank you for coming